<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Martins Blog</title>
    <link>https://martinspielmann.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Martins Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://martinspielmann.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spielmann&#39;s Stricknadel</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-06-19-spielmanns-stricknadel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-06-19-spielmanns-stricknadel/</guid>
      <description>Die Temperatur der Nadel in deutschen Digitalprojeten ist unabhängig von der Umsetzungsgeschwindigkeit.
Egal wie lange gestrickt wird, die Nadel kühlt nicht ab. Selbst bei Projekten, die praktisch stillstehen, bleibt die Nadel stets heiß.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>404 - C2 Not found</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-06-16-c2-not-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-06-16-c2-not-found/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;ve given everything, but C2 just doesn&amp;rsquo;t respond anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo Random Bullshit Generator</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-03-23-pseudo-random-bullshit-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-03-23-pseudo-random-bullshit-generator/</guid>
      <description>Basic building block of IT and especially InfoSec companies: Pseudo Random Bullsh*t Generators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pew Pew - sniper bots on Github to deliver RedLine Stealer</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-03-03-kadenio-uniswap-pancakeswap-sniper-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-03-03-kadenio-uniswap-pancakeswap-sniper-bot/</guid>
      <description>Today, I came across an executable called uniswap-sniperbot-setup.exe that cought my attention. I had no idea what Uniswap and what a sniper bot is.
If you are as curious as me: Uniswap is a crypto, web3, NFT, whatever protocol. And a sniper bot is a program that automates &amp;lsquo;sniping&amp;rsquo;, or placing a last-second bid on an auction item.
Running the executable in a sandbox revealed that it bundles RedLine Stealer malware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Assessment Planets</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-02-26-risk-assessment-planets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-02-26-risk-assessment-planets/</guid>
      <description>Risk of software vulnerabilities being created, risk of being hit by ransomware, &amp;hellip; Seems I found some universal rule here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We must be innovative</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-02-23-we-must-be-innovative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-02-23-we-must-be-innovative/</guid>
      <description>Sure thing, we must explore new paths. And just because others have already gone down these paths does not mean that they are not new to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security Focus Mismatch</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-02-16-cyber-securify-focus-mismatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-02-16-cyber-securify-focus-mismatch/</guid>
      <description>Next audit already in my calendar, not sure about the next attack though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuing your tech people 101</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-01-20-valuing-your-tech-people-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2023-01-20-valuing-your-tech-people-101/</guid>
      <description>Save your praise for sales people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was bei Log4Shell falsch läuft</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-12-14-was-bei-log4shell-falsch-laeuft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-12-14-was-bei-log4shell-falsch-laeuft/</guid>
      <description>Ich muss mich mal auskotzen. Nicht über die Lücke selbst und den Fallout, der uns sicher noch die nächsten Monate begleiten wird, schlimm genug.
Sondern über Leute, die jetzt tatsächlich meinen, die log4j Maintainer anranzen zu müssen.
Was sind das für Anfänger? Die sollten das bezahlen! Nicht zu fassen sowas!&amp;quot;
&amp;hellip;wacht mal auf!
Die Maintainer sind drei Menschen, die ein Projekt am Fliegen halten, das millionenfach in Unternehmen überall auf der Welt genutzt wird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting my offensive journey</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2021-09-13-starting-offensive-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2021-09-13-starting-offensive-journey/</guid>
      <description>As a security engineer in @kiongroup&amp;rsquo;s cyber defense center I help improving detection capabilities, do incident response, automate security processes and work on security best practices. Besides that I develop software at @main_defense.
Although I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated by the creativity of sophisticated attacks, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the defender&amp;rsquo;s side. Time to change that! Today I will start my offensive journey to learn more about the attacker side and how to break things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die Mär vom menschlichen Versagen in der IT-Sicherheit</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2021-03-24-die-mar-vom-menschlichen-versagen-in-der-it-sicherheit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2021-03-24-die-mar-vom-menschlichen-versagen-in-der-it-sicherheit/</guid>
      <description>Human Error. Allseits beliebt und gern herangezogen als ausgemachte Ursache zahlreicher Sicherheitsvorfälle der letzten Monate und Jahre. Die Daten verschlüsselt, das “Backup” feilgeboten, der Konzern blamiert. So weit, so normal. Umsatzeinbruch, Aktieneinbruch, Reputationsverlust.
Menschliches Versagen ist der Hauptgrund für 95% der Sicherheitsvorfälle https://blog.usecure.io/the-role-of-human-error-in-successful-cyber-security-breaches
Die Forensik rückt an, wertet die spärlichen und zur Hälfte wegrotierten Logs aus. Krisenstab, War Room, tagelang. Externe Experten überraschen mit Erkenntnissen zu möglichen Einfallstoren, die das interne Team seit vier Jahren an der Kaffeemaschine vorbetet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 tips on how to save an insane amount of time on clickbait articles (plus 1 bonus)</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2021-01-16-3-tips-on-how-to-save-an-insane-amount-of-time-on-clickbait-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2021-01-16-3-tips-on-how-to-save-an-insane-amount-of-time-on-clickbait-articles/</guid>
      <description>3 tips on how to save an insane amount of time on clickbait articles (plus 1 bonus) &amp;ldquo;AI in medical devices, course or blessing&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;12 ways to earn passive money with no efforts&amp;rdquo;. You are scrolling through social media, click some headlines like the aforementioned ones and an hour later you ask yourself why your feet went to sleep on the toilet again.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate chance to save your feet and a lot of time in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid protoduction fails</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-10-03-how-to-avoid-protoduction-fails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-10-03-how-to-avoid-protoduction-fails/</guid>
      <description>How to avoid protoduction fails &amp;ldquo;Protoduction: a prototype that ends up in production.&amp;rdquo;
Disclaimer first, this term isn&amp;rsquo;t new and appeared on the internet™ in 2011 already. And as you already might suspect, the term has a negative connotation. But why is that? After all, prototypes are built so that the solution will eventually end up in production, aren&amp;rsquo;t they?
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem? &amp;ldquo;A prototype is a simple experimental model of a proposed solution used to test or validate ideas, design assumptions, and other aspects of its conceptualization quickly and cheaply so that the designers involved can make appropriate refinements or possible changes in direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtle bug in Java standard library</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-04-13-java-remove-all-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-04-13-java-remove-all-performance/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled over an interesting Tweet from @relizarov stating
OMG! 😱Don&amp;rsquo;t use Set.removeAll(list) on JVM. You can get O(N^2). I have no words. Only emotions.
As I cound not believe that in the first place, I digged a little deeper and learned about a bug in the Java HashSet implementation with a very long history and finally a fix in sight. It provides a great insight into the complexity of simple things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and UFW</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-02-21-docker-and-ufw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-02-21-docker-and-ufw/</guid>
      <description>The way Docker manipulates iptables actually bypasses ufw, which is the default firewall on Ubuntu systems. You can block a port, spin up a container and in a blink of an eye the blocked port will be open again. It will even bypass Any/Any/Deny rules. To make the magic happen just follow the steps below.
Details Lets see how to reproduce this in detail with the example of a Tomcat container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-02-20-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:50:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/2020-02-20-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post, how exciting!
I will try to dig deeper into everything that went wrong during the working days describe it here, so you do not have to figure out the same pitfalls again. I&amp;rsquo;d love if you join me and send me your daily bad examples. You can do so via any channel you like, the preferred way is to create an issue or PR on codeberg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/page/about/</guid>
      <description>There are countless resources online guiding and teaching you how to design and implement things right. The idea of this blog is doing it the other way round: provide information to not do things wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Protection</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/dataprotection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/dataprotection/</guid>
      <description>1. Datenschutz auf einen Blick Allgemeine Hinweise Die folgenden Hinweise geben einen einfachen &amp;Uuml;berblick dar&amp;uuml;ber, was mit Ihren personenbezogenen Daten passiert, wenn Sie diese Website besuchen. Personenbezogene Daten sind alle Daten, mit denen Sie pers&amp;ouml;nlich identifiziert werden k&amp;ouml;nnen. Ausf&amp;uuml;hrliche Informationen zum Thema Datenschutz entnehmen Sie unserer unter diesem Text aufgef&amp;uuml;hrten Datenschutzerkl&amp;auml;rung.
Datenerfassung auf dieser Website Wer ist verantwortlich f&amp;uuml;r die Datenerfassung auf dieser Website?
Die Datenverarbeitung auf dieser Website erfolgt durch den Websitebetreiber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://martinspielmann.de/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinspielmann.de/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG: Martin Spielmann Spessartstr. 27 63849 Leidersbach
Kontakt Telefon: +49 151 407 48 295 E-Mail: mail@martinspielmann.de Link zur Datenschutzerklärung </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
